TERENCE WESSELS

COVER LETTER

+27 83 443 5390

Dear Hiring Manager



twessels90@gmail.com



Johannesburg, South Africa

terence-wessels-9928036a



I believe the position of Digital Website Project Manager is well suited for me as I have years of professional experience of being part of a strong development team who liaise with clients on a daily basis. Designing a program that truly adds value to the user is my ultimate goal on every project, and I am delighted by the opportunity to apply

My background has involved establishing detailed program specifications through discussions with clients. Breaking down the program specifications into its simplest elements through process mapping and web roadmaps and devising possible solutions to anticipated problems. Conducting testing and installing the program into production. Conducting user-acceptance testing to ensure that the program can be used easily, quickly and accurately as well as adapting the program to new requirements as necessary to ensure client satisfaction.

My strong ability to handle and oversee multiple projects effectively makes me an ideal candidate for this position.

I Have been tasked with managing multiple projects throughout my thirteen years with my current company where I efficiently completed every deliverable on time within budget and with the highest quality to ensure client satisfaction.

With my bachelor's degree in business management and strong development experience and skills like HTML, CSS, Javascript, Node.js and Squarespace. I can bring a lot to the table for this position and bring positive results immediately.

I have patiently been waiting for an opportunity like this and would bring a lot of enthusiasm to this job.

Sincerely



TERENCE WESSELS

PROFILE

+27 83 443 5390



twessels90@gmail.com



terence-wessels-9928036a



Johannesburg, South Africa



WORK EXPERIENCE

N Dec 2018 – Present | Application Developer

challenging working environments.

CBI Electrical, Johannesburg, South Africa

• Establishing a detailed program specification through discussion with clients.

A dynamic and results driven Information Technology Professional who works very

well under pressure. A very fast learner, committed to achieving and exceeding what is expected of me, while remaining focused on the quality of work I provide.

Excellent interpersonal-, communication- and negotiation skills are personal traits I cherish, and I enjoy being part of a successful and productive team that thrives in

- Clarifying what actions, the program is intended to perform.
- Breaking down program specification into its simplest elements and translating this logic into a programming language.
- Devising possible solutions to anticipated problems.
- Working as part of a team, which may be established purely for a particular project to write a specific section of the program.
- Engaging work clients within the company on a daily basis to get a broader understanding of inner workings of the company and how the programs can assist in achieving broader efficiencies and meeting customer needs.
- Combining all elements of the program design and testing it.
- Testing sample data-sets to check that output from the program works as intended.
- Conducting testing and installing the program into production.
- Reacting to problems and correcting the program as necessary.
- Evaluating and increasing the program's effectiveness.
- Adapting the program to new requirements, as necessary.
- Conducting user-acceptance testing to ensure the program can be used easily, quickly and accurately.
- Writing detailed documentation for the operation of the program by users and computer operators.
- Consulting manuals, periodicals and technical reports to learn new ways to develop programs and maintain existing skills and knowledge.
- Updating, repairing, modifying and developing existing software and generic applications.

EDUCATION

2012 - 2017 | BCOMPT

University of South Africa (UNISA)

2008 | Matriculation/Grade 12

Dr. EG Jansen

CERTIFICATIONS

Bachelor of Commerce in Business
Management

Microsoft Certified Solutions Developer

Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate

Microsoft Certified Professional

Business Process Mapping

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Extensive ERP experience

C#

ASP.Net

MVC

ASP.NET Web API

Bootstrap

Crystal Reports

SQL Server

Javascript

Unit Testing

CSS

HTML

Object Orientated Design of Systems

TERENCE WESSELS

WORK EXPERIENCE (Continued)

Sept 2014 - Nov 2018 | BPCS Officer (Business Planning Control Systems)

CBI Electrical, Johannesburg, South Africa

AS/400 User Profile maintenance:

Disabled user profiles deletion Removal of profiles for users that have left

Limited capabilities checked Disable user profiles that are no longer using system

BPCS:

Verify BPCS security authorisation of users

Transaction effect maintenance

1 x Per year BPCS access to maintenance programs Reason code maintenance

AS400 Query reports Table code maintenance

On-going support on BPCS Item class maintenance

BPCS user licences (monthly)

Item type maintenance

Supervision of BPCS input clerk Buyer / Planner maintenance

Training of new users on BPCS CL maintenance for day end / month end / year end

Clean-up BPCS database Check time frame selection at month end

Promotion and Deal set-up I.T Stock-take preparation

Warehouse master maintenance

BPCS Calendars maintenance:

Mps Production (PRDPERP)

Forecast Promotion

Shopfloor

General Admin:

Filing of all I.T documentation Capital Votes (Initiate purchase order etc)

I.T. Consumable administration Asset verification of I.T department

TERENCE WESSELS

Jun 2012 – Aug 2014 | BPCS Administrator (Business Planning Control Systems)

CBI Electrical, Johannesburg, South Africa

- Daily BPCS administration.
- Daily administration of inventory control (INV) on the AS400.
- Daily administration of materials requirements planning (MRP) on the AS400.
- Daily administration of bill of materials (BOM) on the AS400.
- Daily administration of routings (SFC) on the AS400.
- Daily cost adjustments of all products on the AS400.
- Have a strong working relationship with the engineers and the understanding of reading drawings and the requirement for each product structure.
- Filing of all BPCS item masters, routings, structures.
- Stock take auditing.
- Implementation of all ECP's.

May 2009 - May 2012 | Data Capturer & QC

CBI Electrical, Johannesburg, South Africa

- Administration & monthly utilization.
- Writing of reports.
- Monitoring of productivity, efficiency, overall machine efficiency, downtime hours, monthly scrap % monthly scrap value.
- Analysing of components.
- Analysing and testing of materials.
- Intranet queries.
- Observation of AS400 to see locations of stock.

REFEREES

Mr Mervyn De Wet

CBI

I.T Manager

+27 82 447 1378